{
    "id": "ff408d98ab1c4967bb9c7f33f53498a3",
    "title": "Types Of Subordinate Clauses",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ba1a5b60e54d411ea2ce23e85efe6afe",
            "title": "Types Of Subordinate Clauses",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "They serve God well who serve His children.",
                    "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘who serve His children’ modifies the noun God.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Quarrels won’t last long if the fault is only on one side.",
                    "description": "Here the subordinate adverb clause ‘if the fault is only on one side’ modifies the verb ‘last long’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Noun clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "That you should say so surprises me.",
                    "description": "A noun clause can be the subject of a verb. Here the noun clause ‘that you should say so’ is the subject of the verb ‘surprises’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Adjective clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Your statement that you found the money in the closet cannot be believed.",
                    "description": "Here the noun clause ‘that you found the money in the closet’ is in apposition to the noun ‘statement’. Only noun clauses can be used like this.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I asked the boy how old he was.",
                    "description": "Here the noun clause ‘how old he was’ is the object of the verb asked.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Uneasy lies the head that wears the crown.",
                    "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘that wears the crown’ modifies the noun head. Adjective clauses modify nouns and give additional information about them.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Adjective clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Youth is the time when the seeds of character are sown.",
                    "description": "Here the adjective clause when the seeds of character are sown modifies the noun time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Noun clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Servants who are honest are trusted.",
                    "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘who are honest’ modifies the noun servants.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Noun clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Because I like you, I shall help you.",
                    "description": "An adverb clause of reason expresses the reason for the action mentioned in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Noun clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The dog followed the boy wherever he went.",
                    "description": "Here the adverb clause of place ‘wherever he went’ modifies the verb ‘followed’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I like it, I will buy it.",
                    "description": "Adverb clauses of condition are usually introduced by the conjunctions if, whether or unless.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "They spoke in a low voice so that the child would not wake up.",
                    "description": "Here the adverb clause ‘so that the child would not wake up’ expresses the purpose of the action mentioned in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause",
                        "Noun clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}